Guide to the Vassar College Registrar Records, 1865-1998
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar College Registrar Records
1865-1998
Vassar College. Registrar
2 cubic feet (2 boxes, 17 volumes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Course schedules and student records produced by the Vassar College Registrar, including permanent records, grades, and student demographic information.
Scope and Content Note
The records contain course schedules and student records produced by the Vassar College Registrar, including permanent records and student demographic information. The Alphabetical registers contain lists of attending students for each academic year and include date of birth, religious denomination, and city and state of residence. The Alumnae Register contains biographical information. The Matriculation Book contains the signatures of matriculated students. Permanent records contain student grades.
Access
Student permanent records require the permission of a family member to access. Student records recorded after 1930 are restricted to College use only. The remainder of the collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Files on individual students can be found in the Vassar College Alumnae/i Biographical Files (AAVC)
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Vassar College--Alumni and alumnae; Vassar College--Students
Subjects:
Women college students--New York (State)--Poughkeepsiee; Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie
Places:
Poughkeepsie (N.Y.)--History
Document Types:
Catalogs (documents); Registers (lists)
VCL Categories:
Administrative Offices and Functions
Encoding Information
Encoded by Emma Gronbeck, January 2024.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Vassar College Registrar in 2007 [A2007-045] and 2023 [A2023-012].
Series List
- Series I. Course Schedules, 1964-1998
- Series II. Student Records, 1865-1986
Container List
- Series I. Course Schedules, 1964-1998
  - 1964 Sep - 1989 May (Box 1)
  - 1989 Sep - 1998 May (Box 2)
- Series II. Student Records, 1865-1986
  - Alphabetical Record, Vol. 1, 1865 Sep - 1891 May
  - Alphabetical Record, Vol. 2, 1891 Sep - 1925 May
  - Alphabetical Record, Vol. 3, 1925 Sep - 1968 May; [RESTRICTED]
  - Alumnae Register, 1867-1889
  - Matriculation Book, 1917-1986
  - Permanent Record, Vol. 1, 1868 Sep - 1870 May; [RESTRICTED]
  - Permanent Record, Vol. 2, 1870 Sep - 1872 May; [RESTRICTED]
  - Permanent Record, Vol. 3, 1872 Sep - 1874 May; [RESTRICTED]
  - Permanent Record, Vol. 4, 1874 Sep - 1876 May; [RESTRICTED]
  - Permanent Record, Vol. 5, 1876 Sep - 1878 May; [RESTRICTED]
  - Permanent Record, Vol. 6, 1878 Sep - 1881 May; [RESTRICTED]
  - Permanent Record, Vol. 7, 1881 Sep - 1884 May; [RESTRICTED]
  - Permanent Record, Vol. 8, 1884 Sep - 1887 May; [RESTRICTED]
  - Permanent Record, Vol. 9, 1887 Sep - 1890 May; [RESTRICTED]
  - Permanent Record, Vol. 10, 1890 Sep - 1892 May; [RESTRICTED]
  - Permanent Record, Vol. 11, 1892 Sep - 1894 May; [RESTRICTED]
  - Permanent Record, Vol. 12, 1894 Sep - 1896 May; [RESTRICTED]